<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SRA | Academic</title>
    <link>/tag/sra/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/sra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>SRA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 13:12:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>SRA</title>
      <link>/tag/sra/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using google cloud registry for private docker images</title>
      <link>/post/using-google-cloud-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 13:12:54 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/using-google-cloud-registry/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will quickly build a docker image containing the
sra-toolkit and a key for dbGaP downloads. Because the key file is
private, I will be using the secure Google Container Registry to store
the image for later use in genomics workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;background&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Container technologies like &lt;a href=&#34;https://docker.io/&#34;&gt;docker&lt;/a&gt; enable quick and easy
encapsulation of software, dependencies, and operating systems. One or
more containers can render entire software ecosystems portable,
enhance reproducibility and reusability, and facilitate sharing of
software, tools, and even infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/&#34;&gt;DockerHub&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps the most well-known registry where such
docker images can be housed, others such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://quay.io/&#34;&gt;quay.io&lt;/a&gt; are also
available. Commercial cloud environments, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Cloud
Platform&lt;/a&gt; often offer their own registries that use the same secure
access controls as other cloud services, &lt;em&gt;allowing docker images with
proprietary or private information to be stored and accessed
securely&lt;/em&gt;. They are also typically quite integrated with commercial
cloud services (&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/container-registry/docs/&#34;&gt;gcr docs&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am experimenting with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/container-registry/&#34;&gt;Google Container Registry&lt;/a&gt; (GCR) for a
bioinformatics project that I plan to perform in on Google Cloud. This
blog post simply serves as notes to myself about details of using that
system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;preliminaries&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preliminaries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Google Cloud &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/container-registry/docs/quickstart&#34;&gt;account and project&lt;/a&gt; is required to follow along here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/sdk/docs/&#34;&gt;Install the Google Cloud SDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/install/linux/docker-ce/ubuntu/&#34;&gt;Install
Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to allow docker to use google for authorization, we need to
do this one-time command to get tie docker to google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gcloud auth configure-docker&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer “yes” to the prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;building-docker-image-and-adding-to-gcr&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building docker image and adding to GCR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to build a simple docker file that includes the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ncbi/sra-tools&#34;&gt;sra-tools&lt;/a&gt; package, import a private key for downloading files that
are protected, and then store that image to GCR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dockerfile is given below. Note that I &lt;strong&gt;am not including the dbGaP
key file, as it is private&lt;/strong&gt;, but you could modify the Dockerfile to
include your own key file(s) or simply remove the dbGaP access details
entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/seandavi/410cfbbed6b8db0b4928eb36236e7dda.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the container is one line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker build -t sratoolkit .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the docker image has been created. Run it locally to
test, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -ti sratoolkit /bin/bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the docker container, all the sra-toolkit binaries are
available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Google Cloud Project has a private GCR. Therefore, GCR urls
include the &lt;code&gt;PROJECT-ID&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker tag sratoolkit gcr.io/isb-cgc-01-0006/sratoolkit:2.9.2
docker push gcr.io/isb-cgc-01-0006/sratoolkit:2.9.2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;usage&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fun, we can use the image and the &lt;code&gt;fastq-dump&lt;/code&gt; utility to download
a single SRA run. The docker image will only run as long as necessary
to perform the fastq dump and then will terminate. This post is not
about the details of running docker, but note that the following will
result in the fastq file from the &lt;code&gt;fastq-dump&lt;/code&gt; command ending up in
the &lt;code&gt;/tmp&lt;/code&gt; directory on your machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -v /tmp:/data -ti  gcr.io/isb-cgc-01-0006/sratoolkit:2.9.2\
    /bin/bash -c &amp;quot;cd /root/ncbi/dbGaP-16049/ \
    &amp;amp;&amp;amp; fastq-dump   --split-files --gzip \
    --skip-technical -X 10000   SRR390728&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will result in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Read 10000 spots for SRR390728
Written 10000 spots for SRR390728&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;best-practices&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Best practices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing keys, key files, and any other private information in a docker
image is a risky operation and is not a best practice. Leveraging the
security model of GCR mitigates these issues. However, it is &lt;strong&gt;really
easy&lt;/strong&gt; to forget about the information that might be leaked if this
image were shared or pushed to a public repository like DockerHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a discussion of other models for accessing private information
inside a docker container, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctl.io/developers/blog/post/tutorial-protecting-sensitive-info-docker&#34;&gt;this blog post, for example&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;from-here&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From here&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, we have created an environment for building docker
images, stored a proprietary docker image in the Google Cloud
Registry, and successfully used the image to run a simple command to
perform a &lt;code&gt;fastq-dump&lt;/code&gt; with the files ending up on the docker host
machine. This image can be used anywhere a docker image can run, but
only if google authentication &lt;a href=&#34;#preliminaries&#34;&gt;has been tied into docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/genomics/docs/quickstart&#34;&gt;Google Genomics Pipeline API&lt;/a&gt; is built around scalable genomic
workflows and uses docker images for workflow tasks. The image here
can be used for dbGaP genomic data extraction as part of such a
workflow, all within the secure environment of google cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
