<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conference organizing | seandavi(s12)</title>
    <link>/tag/conference-organizing/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/conference-organizing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>conference organizing</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 17:44:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>conference organizing</title>
      <link>/tag/conference-organizing/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symposium: Participants Share Data 2019</title>
      <link>/project/nci-participants-share-data-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 17:44:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/nci-participants-share-data-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We convened a &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.cancer.gov/dccp/pcgdr/agenda&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;symposium on September 26-27,
2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landscape of genomic medicine is rapidly evolving and includes
direct access to low-cost genomic sequencing through
direct-to-consumer genetic testing and commercial services providing
sequencing and interpretation. Increasingly, individuals want to share
their genomic data and associated clinical information for research
purposes. Several models exist to enable personal control of sharing
of genomics data. For individuals who want to make their personal
genomic data available for research or third parties for analysis or
interpretation, little support exists to answer questions, provide
technical support, or give feedback on the value of their data. Under
the auspices of the Cancer Moonshot (sm), NCI welcomes advocates,
policy leaders, and the public to participate in a two-day,
multisession workshop to explore the impact of personal control of
genomic data sharing to research, clinical care, and participants
well-being and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The symposium hosted sessions on the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivations for and perceptions of participants controlling their
own data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitating personal control of sharing data: existing approaches
and platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risks and benefits to participants and their communities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing data in healthcare settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please sign up for our &lt;a href=&#34;https://list.nih.gov/cgi-bin/wa.exe?SUBED1=PARTICIPANTSHAREDDATASYMPOSIUM&amp;amp;A=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; for updates about the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For questions regarding this symposium, email &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:NCIParticipantShareData@mail.nih.gov&#34;&gt;NCIParticipantShareData@mail.nih.gov&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
